Adriano Latorre 622 212 404 adriano@latorre.info

Overview

About me

In love with new media and deeply interested in communication, design and technology.

I feel at home working in a team with agile methodologies. I have an analytical profile and an instinct for synthesis. I am imaginative, curious and always willing to learn.

My portfolio is available at adriano.latorre.info.

Professional skills

- Web architecture, information and interaction design.
- User experience, usability and web accesibility.
- Copywriting.Web design.
- Video and sound editing.
- video and sound editing

Languages

Spanish NativeCatalan Native

English Full professional proficiency

Work experience

July 2018 – Today

Vilynx

Web architecture
Copywriting
User experience
Interaction design
Graphic design
Web design

Vilynx is a startup that uses *machine learning* to develop an artificial intelligence capable of extracting, analyzing and understanding the existing concepts and relationships within any type of textual or audiovisual content.

Together with the design team, I have contributed to establish a good user experience with the redesign and subsequent continuous improvement of the *Dashboard* of Vilynx, the interface that allows programming, consulting and obtaining results from the information analysis that *Brain*—the artificial intelligence algorithm— makes. I have also taken part in the design of the corporate communication for the Vilynx website and for the company presentations.

March 2014 – December 2017

Spines

Web architecture
Copywriting
User experience
Interaction design
Graphic design
Web design

Spines is a startup developing an application to help educational institutions, companies and people to build deep and lasting knowledge.

Using agile methodologies in a self-organized team, I have helped to build the user experience and the design, functionality and appearance of both the application and the Spines website. I have also been in charge of writing —in Spanish and English—most of the Spines message in a multitude of web pages, blog articles, publications in social media and in *Conexiones*, the Spines newsletter.

September 2009 – January 2014

Arista Barcelona

Web architecture
User experience
Copywriting
Web design

Regular collaborator in brainstorming sessions to generate campaigns, creative concepts, UI flows and wireframes for clients such as Nissan, SEAT, Oxfam Intermón, Ajuntament de Barcelona, Caprabo, Danone Yoghourtería, Dentaid, Iris

Barcelona and Autopistas.

September 2007 – August 2009

Freelance

Web architecture Copywriting Web design Independent consulting, web architecture, copywriting and web design for clients such as Médicos Sin Fronteras and Gnoss.

March 2000 – July 2007

httpcomunicació

Web architecture

Copywriting Multimedia development Video editing Web design Web designer and interactive CD developer in the early years. Gradually, I grew more interested in web architecture and copywriting. Regular participant in brainstorming sessions and responsible for projects from beginning to delivery.

Clients: Abertis, Grupo Husa, Médicos Sin Fronteras, Oxfam Intermón, Arsys, Piensa Solutions, butxaca, Querida Carmen, Buff, Cibernàrium, Barcelona Activa and many more.

October 1997 – February 2000

Freelance

Copywriting
Multimedia development
Video editing
Web design

First freelance professional projects and frequent collaborations with companies such as MDK Servimedia and Spectra.

Education

September 1997 – August 2001

Multimedia Graduate at Universitat Oberta de Catalunya.

September 1996 – August 1997

Multimedia master's degree at Universitat de Barcelona – Les Heures.

September 1994 – August 1996

Philology and Linguistics at University of Barcelona.

Contact

Phone Mail

adriano@latorre.info

622 212 404

Portfolio

Residence

adriano.latorre.info

Barcelona